The U.S.
has just struck a deal
with Venezuela
to control more than 65
billion barrels
of its proven oil
reserves.
Trump has said
this will basically
double the U.S.
oil reserves
and substantially lower
gas prices for all
Americans.
Some analysts
have reacted
with skepticism,
including whether
the deal will address
longstanding obstacles
that have deterred
investments
in Venezuela's oil
industry.
The U.S.
Secretary of State
has said that this deal
will bring over $100
billion
to the Venezuelan people
and private investments,
and basically help
reconstruct
the Venezuelan economy.
This deal, the U.S.
is retaining a 55%
control of this joint
venture, and that there
has been no precedent
so far of the U.S.
government entering
into a lease to operate
Venezuelan oil fields.
We're not really too
sure if this move
will sort of violate
Venezuela's constitution
or its hydrocarbons law.
I assume this will sort
of affect things later
down the line a couple
years later, rather than
in a couple months
for oil prices.